今天我想谈谈走哪
today I'd like to talk about GO which
有趣的是特别有趣
is interesting especially interesting
我们在这个过程中，因为课程GO
for us in this course because course GO
在你所有的实验室语言
is the language at the labs you're all
打算做实验室的，所以我想
going to do the labs in and so I want to
今天特别注重一些
focus today particularly on some of the
机械那种最有用的
machinery that sort of most useful in
在实验室和最特别
the labs and in most particular to
分布式编程嗯首先是
distributed programming um first of all
你知道它的价值追问为什么我们使用Go
you know it's worth asking why we use go
在这个类其实我们可以使用
in this class in fact we could have used
其他一些系统中的任一
any one of a number of other system
风格语言很多语言，如
style languages plenty languages like
Java或C尖锐，甚至是Python的
Java or C sharp or even Python that
提供一种设备，我们需要
provide the kind of facilities we need
而事实上，我们使用这个用C ++
and indeed we used to use C++ in this
类，它制定了罚款，它会去
class and it worked out fine it'll go
确实像许多其他语言
indeed like many other languages
提供一堆其是特征
provides a bunch of features which are
特别方便
particularly convenient
这对线程的良好支持和
that's good support for threads and
锁定和同步之间
locking and synchronization between
我们使用了大量的线程它是一个
threads which we use a lot it is a
方便的远程过程调用包
convenient remote procedure call package
这听起来并不像很多，但它
which doesn't sound like much but it
其实原来是一个显著
actually turns out to be a significant
从语言，如C ++约束
constraint from in languages like C++
例如，它实际上是一个有点难以
for example it's actually a bit hard to
找到一个方便好用的远程使用
find a convenient easy to use remote
过程调用封装，当然，我们的
procedure call package and of course we
用它所有的时间在此过程中或
use it all the time in this course or
程序和不同的机器来说话
programs and different machines to talk
对方不像C ++走的是类型安全
to each other unlike C++ go is type safe
和内存安全的是它是相当困难
and memory safe that is it's pretty hard
到程序编写，由于一个bug
to write a program that due to a bug
在一些随机一块涂鸦
scribbles over some random piece of
内存，然后导致程序做
memory and then causes the program to do
神秘的东西，只是
mysterious things and that just
消除了一个很大的错误类的相似
eliminates a big class of bugs similarly
它的垃圾回收，这意味着你
it's garbage collected which means you
从来没有在普里阿摩斯相同的内存危险
never in danger of priam the same memory
两次或可用内存这是仍在使用
twice or free memory that's still in use
什么垃圾矢量刚
or something the garbage vector just
停止使用的时候事情的FreeS
frees things when they stop being used
一件事是，也许不是很明显
and one thing it's maybe not obvious
直到你眼前这个发挥各地
until you played around with just this
那种前编程，但
kind of programming before but the
线程和垃圾的组合
combination of threads and garbage
收集就显得尤为重要一个
collection is particularly important one
的是，在非不顺心的事
of the things that goes wrong in a non
垃圾回收语言如C ++，如果
garbage collected language like C++ if
您使用线程的是，它总是一个
you use threads is that it's always a
一个谜和位需要一堆
bit of a puzzle and requires a bunch of
簿记弄清楚当最后
bookkeeping to figure out when the last
线
thread
目前正使用一个共享对象具有
that's using a shared object has
使用该对象，因为只完成
finished using that object because only
那么你可以释放对象，你结束
then can you free the object as you end
写出来大衣颇有几分滋味
up writing quite a bit of coat it's like
手动它是关于一个程序员
manually the programmer it's about a
一串代码手动你知道做
bunch of code to manually you know do
为了引用计数或某事
reference counting or something in order
找出你知道当最后
to figure out you know when the last
使用对象的线程停止
thread stopped using an object and
这只是一个痛苦和问题
that's just a pain and that problem
完全消失，如果你使用垃圾
completely goes away if you use garbage
集合就像我们已经回不去
collection like we haven't go
最后语言简单得多
and finally the language is simple much
比的问题C ++一个简单
simpler than C++ one of the problems
使用C ++的是，往往如果你做
with using C++ is that often if you made
一个错误，你知道，也许甚至只是一个错字
an error you know maybe even just a typo
你找回错误信息
the the error message you get back from
编译器非常复杂，在
the compiler is so complicated that in
C ++它通常不是值得尝试
C++ it's usually not worth trying to
弄清楚错误消息是什么意思
figure out what the error message meant
我觉得它永远只是更快
and I find it's always just much quicker
去看看行号，并尝试
to go look at the line number and try to
你猜怎么着错误一定是
guess what the error must have been
因为语言是太
because the language is far too
复杂
complicated
而走的是你知道的可能不
whereas go is you know probably doesn't
有很多人喜爱的功能
have a lot of people's favorite features
但它是相对简单
but it's relatively straightforward
语言在这一点上你没事所以
language okay so at this point you're
无论在教程如果你正在寻找
both on the tutorial if you're looking
对于那种你知道该看什么
for sort of you know what to look at
接下来，了解语言的好
next to learn about the language a good
地方看是标题文档
place to look is the document titled
你知道你可以找到有效的去
effective go which you know you can find
在网上搜索没事第一
by searching the web all right the first
总之，我要谈的是主题
thing I want to talk about is threads
为什么我们非常关心的原因
the reason why we care a lot about
在此过程中的线程是线程
threads in this course is that threads
是那种我们将主要工具
are the sort of main tool we're going to
使用并发性的管理中
be using to manage concurrency in
程序和并发性是一个特别的
programs and concurrency is a particular
在分布式编程的兴趣
interest in distributed programming
因为通常的情况是一个
because it's often the case that one
程序实际上需要跟一个
program actually needs to talk to a
一堆的其他计算机，你知道客户端
bunch of other computers you know client
可能会谈到多台服务器或服务器可以
may talk to many servers or a server may
要在服务上同时请求
be serving requests at the same time on
代表许多不同的客户等的
behalf of many different clients and so
我们需要一种方法来说，哦，你知道我是我
we need a way to say oh you know I'm my
节目真的有七个不同
program really has seven different
事情怎么回事，因为它说话
things going on because it's talking to
七种不同的客户，我想
seven different clients and I want a
简单的方法，使其能够做到这七个
simple way to allow it to do these seven
你知道没有太多不同的事情
different things you know without too
很多复杂的编程我的意思是那种
much complex programming I mean sort of
推力线程是答案所以这些
thrust threads are the answer so these
是的东西，旅途中的文档
are the things that the go documentation
电话将转到我称之为线程程序
calls go routines which I call threads
他们走程序是真的这同
they're go routines are really this same
因为别人都调用
as what everybody else calls
红这么认为线程的方法是
Red's so the way to think of threads is
你有一个程序的程序
that you have a program of one program
和一个地址空间我要画一个
and one address space I'm gonna draw a
箱排序表示一个地址空间
box to sort of denote an address space
并在该地址空间内
and within that address space in a
无绪串行程序你只是
serial program without threads you just
有执行执行一个线程
have one thread of execution executing
在该地址空间中的程序代码
code in that address space one program
寄存器中的一个堆叠的计数器的一组
counter one set of registers one stack
是那种描述当前的
that are sort of describing the current
在带螺纹的执行的状态
state of the execution in a threaded